<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on caldito.me</title>
    <link>/talks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on caldito.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(Workshop) Reclaiming privacy in the web with Whonix in KVM</title>
      <link>/talks/reclaiming-privacy-whonix-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/reclaiming-privacy-whonix-kvm/</guid>
      <description>Resources  Notes for following the workshop Slides  Notes: Disclaimer: this is just a quick outline I used for presenting and may contain errors
1. Introduction 2. Virtualization Platforms: Hypervisors and emulators Hypervisors: hardware virtualization Virtualize only the Operating system on top of the original hardware
 Type FOSS or not  Emulators Virtualize the hardware architecture.
 QEMU quick emulator. Open source and 7 different architectures Useful for gaming and virtualising legacy hardware Rosetta: very relevant in apple devices with ARM architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform Engineering in the Homelab</title>
      <link>/talks/platform-engineering-in-the-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/platform-engineering-in-the-homelab/</guid>
      <description>Resources  Recording Slides  Notes: Disclaimer: this is just a quick outline I used for presenting and may contain errors
What is self-hosting and why to do it Self-hosting is running your own services for personal use.
Why:
 Your data is yours It&amp;rsquo;s a fun hobby if you are a nerd Learn about service operations or improving your skills  Example services:
 Photos (Immich) Files (Owncloud/nextcloud/synchthing) A fully legal (wink) replacement for video subscription services Notes Maps Books Calendar Contacts Mail Bookmarks LLM chatbot  For these things you can either use the cloud or build a homelab.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
